hey everyone this is Kat at explore
issue on YouTube and in this video I'm
going to share something really
extraordinary with you and I think
you're going to really like it because I
have proof
of some of the new words that we found
in the King James Bible
and this was found by
um a YouTuber by the name of H Kovacs
84.
and she discovered that in the back of
her Holy Bible
The Study Edition of the King James
version
I have a cover right here
that she had an appendix in the back of
her book
that have 500
of the new words in the King James Bible
this is amazing
this is very similar to the insert
that some of us have in our in our
Bibles the Queen Elizabeth insert is
what I call it
and what's really exciting about this
friends is that it outlines the word
switches
and we're going to go through those
together right now and I also will go
ahead and leave a link to the original
YouTuber who actually videotaped
um her Bible and what I did is I went
through her video and I took screenshots
because I wanted to highlight some
things that she didn't
um I'm also I also went ahead and I I
created a PDF document and it's a
PowerPoint document that you can go
ahead and download so you can go and
have this as evidence
and part of your study to look over the
words that have been switched
and feel free to share them with as many
people as you know because this is
really amazing
now for those of you who don't know our
bibles are being changed supernaturally
it's extraordinary
and I've seen the words change
at an accelerated rate in the last three
months and it's been you know well
devastating right because the Bible has
always been such a source of
um security and strength for me and all
of a sudden we have all these
foreign word Invaders
and it's not just the King James Bible
that's being changed every translation
is under attack
and it's become increasingly evident
that they are attacking the deity of
Jesus Christ
while promoting the Antichrist and
just evil it's incredible and some of
these words which is you'll get what I'm
talking about because they're redefining
the the judeo-christian story
and some of the word switches as I've
gone over with you in my previous videos
really don't make sense they change the
meaning of the sentence
and they're not even using synonyms as
we'll find out
so let's go ahead and take a look
um at these changes
and forgive me because I have a bad cold
and a sore throat right now so
pardon me if if we get interrupted
but let's go ahead and take a look at
the appendix
so here's what it says words that have
changed in meaning
the following is a list of over 500
archaic and obsolete words and phrases
in the King James Bible along with their
contemporary equivalence to help the
modern reader understand more readily
the meaning of the King James version
each expression is followed by those
passages
containing the expression particularly
likely to cause some degree of
misunderstanding
the term from the King James text is in
bold face
followed by its modern equivalent where
more than one possible equivalent exists
each is numbered and down with the
corresponding passages every effort has
been made to express each equivalent in
a form that exactly fits the grammatical
structure
of the King James text
although this list is not exhaustive it
provides the modern reader with a handy
reference to those terms and expressions
most likely to produce difficulty in
comprehending the meaning of the King
James version
so
let's get started so I took screenshots
of the video so this is what we get
and what I want you to see friends is
the words that are bold are the words
that are in the King James Bible
and the words that are italicized are
the ones they've replaced
sometimes because I have found what I've
looked through this list
that sometimes is vital size word that's
in scripture and not the Bold one
but and then also they don't reference
every single change this is only a
fraction of them as it even states in
the introduction
but what I think is most interesting is
to look through
this list of words
and see what they changed it with
because you'll see that many of them
don't even make sense
they're not synonyms
I mean sometimes it means something
entirely different
and I don't even know how they even came
up with a word switch
except that they have an agenda
so you can take a look through this and
see
um you know you can see that the the
bold words are words that were never in
scripture before
at least most of them and now they are
and some of these words don't even make
sense like for this word
the word prove was replaced with the
word Ellen and I don't know what alleges
I mean do you
I don't know what it could mean
the word Terror was replaced with
amazement
and I don't understand that either
except that what they want to do is
confuse the reader
that's the only explanation friends is
to be confusing and to tell a different
story
because if you change a word even as
little as a preposition it can change
the whole meaning of the sentence
so then we have these words
in the opposite column
and you can see here that they've
replaced the word Elder with ancient
the word immediately with Anon
perfumer with apothecary
defense with answer and it just goes on
and on and on elbows with armholes
weapons with artillery
incredible
it just really doesn't make sense these
word changes except that they want to
confuse
now not every King James Bible has this
insert I have four King James Bible and
I have no insert in mine do you
so let me just go down this list it then
this is ridiculous it said how the word
couch in it it didn't have the word
couch in it and change it with bed so
these are other mistakes that we're
seeing even in this insert it's not 100
accurate
um I thought it was interesting that
they changed the word body to belly
and they're calling that a modern
replacement
or lay its heart now becomes be think
themselves does that make sense or early
becomes the times
or a maze becomes Bewitched
office became Bishop prick
and I knew bishopric was wrong because
it actually means a Roman Catholic
bishop
and that's totally wrong it's total word
switch and in our Bibles we have a k at
the end
it doesn't end in the sea
and if you just go down this list you
can just see somebody the new word
inserts that we've already discussed or
word switches wine skins become bottles
of wine same with drunkenness
and then we have for heart
or Compassion or affection or English
becomes vowels
have you ever heard of such a thing it's
ridiculous but it's meant to deceive
and then we have words like breaking in
are now substituted with breaking up
and possession is now for breeding
coats of mail which we've already talked
about because we still have coats of
mail in scripture and we also have
brigandines
so see that's another mistake there
because we have both in scripture right
now
immediately has been replaced with by
and by
not in every instance but in some and
then the word anxious has been replaced
with careful
that's why you have Philippians 4 6 no
longer says be anxious for nothing but
it says be careful for nothing
and I did a video about that
um
and then we move along
I think this is interesting some of
these words I've never even heard of
like capital I don't remember capital in
Scripture
but it looks like it's been replaced
with chapter
I've never heard a chapter and look love
replaced charity
the word chastisement was replaced with
the word check
I mean isn't this ridiculous or
completely it was replaced with clean
I don't know if these people who did
this expected anybody to read this the
word border or boundary
in the Old Testament was changed to
Coast
or even territory how ridiculous is that
and then we see the outer replaced uh
the word cockatrice replace the word
outer
and look at this gather was replaced
with call-ups
call UPS have you ridiculous that's not
a modern change of words
and then we have these words here well
actually it's a for the scrolling
further down
um you know we have communication we
talked about that before and it was it
replaced the word companionship or
Fellowship
oh and look friends remember I said the
compass was a new new word and we know
that's a very Mason symbol it used to be
the word Circle or in compass
and then we have the word concluded
uh replace the word shut up actually
friends shut up is still in scripture
and I find it extremely offensive
the word spice is now confection
and then this is interesting friends
because we have the word destruction was
replaced with the word consumption
and we have words like grain
was replaced with the word corn can you
believe that so you know we see that in
our Bibles that Joseph is gathering corn
in Scripture it's ridiculous
and then we have
words like cakes which I don't remember
in scripture well yeah actually I do
remember First Kings was replaced with
the word cracknels
and then prostrate was replaced with
Crouch
and seagull was replaced with cuckoo
cuckoo
um how is that modern friends
I don't understand
and then we have the word devoted thing
was replaced with curse
so do you see how these words aren't
even synonyms and they do these word
substitutions that have
there's no
excuse me there's no parallel meaning
here
and then the word condemnation
and judgment
has now been replaced to damnation
isn't that incredible
and then we have words like
condemned is now Damned
dear life is now darling
entice is deceived
it's just really interesting to see how
they've changed these words
you know it's it's really quite
appalling to me
naturally
and then we have words like
um condemned and found guilty is now
turned to desolate
um goat demons and Saturns are now
Devils but I I know there's a Saturn
scripture
um the word
teachers has now been changed to doctors
ridiculous
jackals and sea monsters are dragons
that's why we have dragons popping up
all over the place in scripture now and
the word chief was changed to Duke and I
can tell you for certain and princesses
Duke is in scripture way too many times
and it's ridiculous
then we have all these other new words
like eared and earring where I mean how
is plowed the same as ear to earring or
plowing the same as earring
you see how ridiculous this is and I'm
saying that earring is the most modern
and then you have the word carefully is
now earnestly ring is earring
Passover became Easter tumors became
emerods
Council became a state
incredible
and then oh see fan window became fan
winnowing Fork became fan
and winners became fanners interesting
and then we have more words here oh
Compass it looks like it became Environ
that's interesting
and then we have the word
um
task Masters became exactors
um Hewer became Feller
oh this is interesting you guys
um
make a circuit or turnabout became
fetched a compass
I mean no one even uses that word now
um spelled a kind of wheat became
fitches
cakes of raisins became flagons
oh look at this you guys impurity became
flowers
and Nations for became folk in
isn't that ridiculous have you ever
heard of such a thing
and then we have
frightened became Fray
perverse and crooked became froward
I've gone over many of these words with
you
the word filled became furnished
saddle became furniture
I mean unbelievable you can't make this
up
you know oh breed became gender
see friends they really are so crooked
in their ways they really are
changing the meaning of of scripture
through these word switches
I mean in some of these words
you know it's just ridiculous
and then we have words like
um
limped became halt
which is really interesting to look
through these
um
leech became horse leech hamstring
became half
whoops
um stubbornness became imagination
I just don't really understand how they
came up with these words because they're
not even synonyms you know what I mean
so interesting
weapon became instrument
doings became inventions
jeopardize became jeoparded look Judea
became jewelry
that's an offensive word
justice became judgment in fact that
reminds me
there's a saying that says you know
righteousness and Justice are the
foundations of his throne
well now it's righteousness and judgment
are the foundations of his throne the
other thing that I think is interesting
is that judgment is now misspelled
because I remember judgment with an e
j-u-d-g-e-m-e-n-t
you know you just go down this list and
you can see all the word changes like
lies and falsehood
change to leasing I mean how is that a
modern word friends
I don't understand
except that it doesn't make sense
um
look at this juice became liquor
I didn't know that I didn't I didn't see
that word that's a new word
the chamber became Loft
epileptic became lunatic
virgin became made
it's interesting
um Club became Mall ruined what became
marred
Common Man became mean man well friends
we do have common man in Scripture
we definitely we have common people and
Common Man
meal became meat so did food and you
have to ask yourself why I've covered
this actually in a video
they're sending a message
and then we have
um Merchant became Merchant man
attendant became Minister flute player
flute players are now minstrels
it's ridiculous
stronghold became munition
naughty knit wickedness wickedness in
James 1 21 became naughtiness and look
grandchildren became nephews does that
even make sense
and then we have
um you know scrolling down
olive oil is now oil olive
frequent has become open
pipe is organs
jewelry settings is now ouches
overburden is overcharged ostriches are
now owls
you know and we just keep going on and
on with these word changes that many of
them don't even make sense
is it any wonder why scriptures mean
something totally different
but that they're redefining the
Christian story
creating apostasy
causing people to be led astray
it's really devious
we move along
the word formed is now possessed
okay I don't like that at all because
that's in Psalm 139
believable
um
the word inscribed
is now called printed
secretly is privily I mean I've never
even heard of privilege until I saw it
in scripture recently
foreign
trails are now pertinents
and look they changed the word alive to
quick
I mean I never heard of such a thing
but it's made to deceive these word
switches are with this distinct purpose
of creating confusion
um
witness was changed to record
kidneys was changed to range although we
still find kidneys in Scripture
um
it's just really interesting friends to
see all these isn't it
but all these words are now in Scripture
and I find it incredible and I'm sure
you do too how can you not
how can you know how does this not take
your breath away by seeing all these
word switches that are recent
and to find a whole list in the back of
somebody's Bible
is remarkable
you know counsel has become Secret
pouch and bag are now called scrip a
wild goat became a sadder
you know Elders is now ancients or
senators
decency has become shame facedness
and look friends the acacia tree has
become a shitta tree and a tree
I think both of those words are really
offensive
the innermost Parts have now become
sides
do you see how they're redefining
everything friends
you know pant for air has now become
Snuffy snuffed up the wind
take no Delight in is change the smell
I mean what relationship does take no
Delight in have with smell
none
none whatsoever
loathsome is now sorrowful
chords is now sorrows
unbelievable
distress is now straightened
and then we have you know words like
pasture lands and precincts are now
suburbs
baggage stuffs
strive is steady
Aramaic is now Syrian
tablet is now tables we've gone over
that armlets are now tablets
be not anxious is changed to take no
thought
ridiculous now you know of course I
meant we have Target in scripture now
by Design
you know we have words like
um
from okay now listen to this from was
changed to toward
transferred is now to translated
think is now trial
doves is now Turtles and look friends
wild ox is now unicorns
an unformed is now unperfect
and they're calling these modern words
the word wandering is now vagabond
falsehood is Vanity
Justice is vengeance
don't you find this interesting friends
the word new is now with
and open is now void
maidservant is now wench
wine skins is not wine bottles
and look friends tasty morsels is now
wounds
anyway I think it's very interesting and
worth your effort worth your time to go
through
this word list and at least to download
it and have it ready and you know put in
your Bible or keep it near you in a file
to be able to refer back to and even to
go through your Bible and change the
words
I mean it clearly does not make sense
I'd like to hear from you I'd like to
know what you think about this list of
words
do you think that these new words are
actually modern
because I don't
I don't even think these words which is
even make sense most of the time
and it's clearly meant to deceive and
that's what they're doing
they're they're causing confusion
and I know be on a shadow of a doubt it
is not God
authorizing these changes in scripture
because that would make him a liar
God is allowing the changes to happen in
order to fulfill Bible prophecy but the
enemy is the one who's literally
um leading this charge
along with his fallen angels to make
this happen
and it's unbelievable to me
it really is
I still can't believe it
and all I have to do is look at some
word switches and I'm reminded that yes
it's happening
and it's Grievous but we're one day
closer to that day
that we long for
and so
friends I want to hear from you what do
you think about this this insert do you
have this insert this word list in the
back of your Bible you should check
um
with that said friends be strong and
courageous do not fear be dismayed for
the Lord your God is with you wherever
you go until next time